Werner, Alfred; Papers ger096
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Alfred Werner Papers
1903-1979
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger096
23 cubic ft.
The Alfred Werner Papers contain typescripts of his writings on artists and art topics, as well as a small amount of correspondence, student papers, notes and research materials used for his writing. Werner's main focus was on Jewish art and artists.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
The Alfred Werner Papers were donated to the University Libraries of the State University of New York by his widow, Lisa Werner, on November 2, 1981.
Biographical Sketch
Alfred Werner was born Alfred Weintraub on March 30, 1911. Both his mother, Frederika (née Silberstein) and father, Ignatz Weintraub, were born in the former Polish city of Lwow (Lemberg), but relocated to Vienna in 1898, where Ignatz studied law at the University of Vienna, and where both Alfred and his brother Edward (1914) were born. Both sons followed their father into the study of law, although Alfred was encouraged early by his teachers to study philology.
Werner studied law at the University of Vienna from 1929 to 1934, but also took courses in German literature, philology, pedagogy, history, and geography, with aspirations of a teaching career. After his graduation from the University, he continued his literary pursuits, writing for the Jewish publication Die Stimme and Gerechtigkeit, and publishing a volume of poetry under the title Gebet aus der Tiefe in 1936. During this time, he also lectured at the extension division of the University of Vienna and acted as literary director of the Jüdische Kulturstelle in Vienna. His career was cut short when he was arrested in 1938 and sent to the concentration camp Dachau, where he spent nearly a year, until he was allowed to immigrate to England in 1939. During the summer of 1940, Werner was again briefly interned, this time in the Kitchener Camp near Sandwich, England, awaiting a U.S. visa. Werner wrote articles for the camp publication, The Kitchener Review, and continued to write poetry describing his experiences of exile and internment.
In 1940, Werner arrived in New York City, spent a year mastering his English language skills, and by 1941 was freelance writing articles and reviews for the The New York Times, Kenyon Review, Commentary and Arts Magazine. He became an editor for the Universal Jewish Encyclopedia in 1941 and continued until 1945. During the late 1940s, Werner continued to pursue his freelance career and also held editorial positions on the Chicago Jewish Forum and later Survey Reports.
Werner spent the years from 1949 to 1952 absorbed in the study of art history at the Institute of Fine Arts of New York University, the beginning of his career as an art historian and serious art critic. From 1953 until his death in 1979, Werner published no less than 20 monographs on such artists as Ernst Barlach, Marc Chagall, Edgar Degas, Amedeo Modigliani, Chaim Soutine, Moses Soyer, and Max Weber, as well as over 2,000 articles and reviews on artists and art topics, including his regular monthly article series, "Views and Visions", for the magazine Art Voices.
Werner was married three times, but had no children. His first wife, Gertrude "Trudy", a psychoanalyst, emigrated with Werner to the United States in 1940, but died shortly thereafter. Werner married his second wife, Judith, in 1953, who died in the late 1960s. He was married to his third wife, Lisa, from 1975 until his death on July 14, 1979.
Chronology of Events
1911 Born March 30 in Vienna, Austria to Frederika (b. Silberstein) and Ignatz Weintraub.
1914 Birth of brother, Edward.
1918-1929 Attended elementary and secondary schools in Vienna; graduated Spring 1929.
1929-1934 Studied law at the University of Vienna; graduated with degree of Dr. jur.
1935-1936 Worked for the publications Die Stimme and Gerechtigkeit (Vienna).
1935-1938 Lectured at extension division of University of Vienna.
1936-1938 Literary director of Jüdische Kulturstelle in Vienna.
1938-1939 Interned in Dachau concentration camp.
1939 Emigrated to England.
1940 Summer, interned in Kitchener Camp near Sandwich, England; wrote articles for the Kitchener Camp Review.
1940 Emigrated to the United States.
1941-1945 Editor, The Universal Jewish Encyclopedia; also wrote articles for the New York Times, the Kenyon Review, Commentary and Arts Magazine.
1941-1945 Short association with the Office of War Information (OWI).
1943-1960 Associate editor, Chicago Jewish Forum.
1945 Became naturalized U.S. citizen.
1946-1950 Consultant for the Office of Jewish Affairs, American Jewish Congress; consultant for Survey Reports.
1948-1949 Editor of Little Book Art Series.
1949-1952 Student of fine arts at Institute of Fine Arts, New York University.
1953 Editor of Survey Reports; married second wife, Judith Mayer.
1955-1958 Lecturer in the school of General Studies at City College and Wagner College, CUNY.
1956-1978 Art Consultant for the Theodor Herzl Institute, New York City.
1967 Awarded prof. honoris causa by the Austrian Ministry of Education.
1975 Married Lisa Tramm in March.
1979 Died on July 14 in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The Alfred Werner Papers is divided into eight series and contains typescripts of his writings on artists and art topics, as well as a small amount of correspondence, student papers, notes and research materials used for his writing. Werner's main focus was on Jewish art and artists. Included in the collection are: typescripts and research materials for his monographs, essayistic writings and reviews; a small amount of correspondence with famous artists, including Achiam, Abdullah Alkara, Mordecai Ardon, Otto Bihalj-Merion, Marc Chagall, Isac Friedlander, Erich Heckel, Marcel Janco, Benjamin Kopman, Alfred Rubens, Michael Schreck, Ben Shahn, and Anna Ticho; as well as copious research notes and supporting materials.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Biographical and Autobiographical Materials, ca. 1939-1976, Undated
Series 2 - Correspondence, 1942-1949, Undated
Series 3 - Writings: Poetry, Stories, 1939-1947, Undated
Series 4 - Writings: Monographs of Artists, 1935-1979, Undated
Series 5 - Writings: Articles on Artists, 1903-1979, Undated
Series 6 - Writings: Articles on Art Topics, 1921-1978, Undated
Series 7 - Writings: Book Reviews, Undated
Series 8 - Writings: Miscellaneous, 1958-1973, Undated
Art; Architecture; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; Austrians--United States.; Jews--Austria--Vienna.; Journalists--United States.; Art Historians--United States.; Jewish Art; Jewish Artists; World War, 1939-1945--Poetry.; New York (N.Y.); Sandwich (England); Correspondence; Poetry; Reviews (document genre); Essays; typescripts; Articles; Clippings; Research Notes; Exhibition catalogs; Werner, Alfred, 1911-1979; Chagall, Marc, 1887-1985; Barlach, Ernst, 1870-1938; Modigliani, Amedeo, 1884-1920; Pascin, Jules, 1885-1930; Soutine, Chaim, 1893-1943; Soyer, Moses, 1899-1974
- Biographical and Autobiographical Materials, ca. 1939-1976; Undated; 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains only a small amount of materials, but includes a short autobiographical sketch, written by Werner shortly after coming to the United States, as well as lexicon and other articles describing Werner's work as an art historian.
  - "Curriculum vitae", ca. 1939 (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 1)
  - Bibliography of published articles, 1949-1958 (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 2)
  - Lexicon and newspapers articles on Werner, 1955-1976 (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 3)
  - Letterhead, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 4)
  - Lecture outlines, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical and Autobiographical Materials), Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1942-1949; Undated; 2
  Arranged alphabetically.
  One folder of correspondence contains primarily letters to libraries and publishers, in request of information on Werner's research interests. The second folder contains Undated "letters to the editor" written by Werner. There are also small amounts of correspondence scattered throughout the collection and filed under the subject of the correspondence. As can be noted, Werner often re-used the backs of letters received to take notes on various topics.
  - Letter to Editors, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence concerning publications, 1942-1949 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
- Writings: Poetry, Stories, 1939-1947; Undated; 3
  Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically within folders.
  This series contains Werner's early belletristic writings, primarily poetry. Many of the English poems, as well as the prose writings, written between 1939 and 1940, describe the experiences of exile, internment in a British labor camp, as well as Werner's voyage and early days in the United States.
  - Collection of poems in English, 1939 (Box 1 (3-Writings: Poetry, Stories), Folder 8)
  - Individual poems, in English, A-K, 1939-1940 (Box 1 (3-Writings: Poetry, Stories), Folder 9)
  - Individual poems, in English, L-Z, 1939-1940 (Box 1 (3-Writings: Poetry, Stories), Folder 10)
  - Poetry in English, 1939-1940 (Oversized 22, Folder 10)
  - Short essays, in English, printed in The Kitchner Camp Review, 1940 (Oversized 22, Folder 11)
  - Collections of poems, in German, 1946-1947 (Box 1 (3-Writings: Poetry, Stories), Folder 11-12)
  - Individual poems, in German, 1944-1947 (Box 1 (3-Writings: Poetry, Stories), Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous prose writings, in German, Undated (Oversized 22, Folder 12)
- Writings: Monographs of Artists, 1925-1979; Undated; 4
  This series contains typescripts, proofs, handwritten and typed notes, a small amount of correspondence, clippings, exhibition catalogs, and photographs pertaining to the monographs written by Werner on the artists: Ernst Barlach, Marc Chagall, Edgar Degas, Albrecht Dürer, Raoul Dufy, Paul Gauguin, Chaim Gross, George Inness, Gustav Klimt, Amedeo Modigliani, Edvard Munch, Jules Pascin, Odilon Redon, Michael Schreck, Chaim Soutine, Moses Soyer, Maurice Utrillo and Max Weber. In addition to texts of the monographs, the series also contains numerous typescripts (as well as some published versions) of short articles and reviews of books dealing with these same artists.
  - Barlach, Ernst. Correspondence concerning research on Barlach monograph, 1962-1963 (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 14)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Transcript of speech by Barlach, "Der Künstler und seine Zeit", 23 Jan 1933 (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 15)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Alfred Werner:Ernst Barlach, 1966; Typescript. 63p. (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 16)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Alfred Werner:Ernst Barlach, 1966; Typescript. 64p. (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 17)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Alfred Werner:Ernst Barlach, 1966; Typescript. 78p. (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 18)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Alfred Werner:Ernst Barlach, 1966; Miscellaneous typescript pages (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 19)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Alfred Werner:Ernst Barlach reviews, 1966 (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 20)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Typescripts of various short essays by Werner on Barlach, Undated (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 21)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Typescripts of untitled essays by Werner on Barlach, Undated (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 22)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 23-24)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Notes on Barlach ownership, Undated (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 25)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Naomi Jackson Groves:Ernst Barlach. Ph.D. thesis, 1950 (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 26)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Clippings, exhibit materials, in English, 1950s-1970s (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 27)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Clippings, in German, 1950s-1970s (Box 1 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 28)
  - Barlach, Ernst. Photographs of artwork, Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 1)
  - Ernst Barlach Haus, Ernst Barlach Gesellschaft. Clippings, materials, 1960s (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 2)
  - Chagall, Marc and Valentina, general correspondence, 1959-1976; 1 L. by Chagall; 3 L. by Valentina Chagall (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 3)
  - Chagall, Marc. Clippings of short articles by Chagall, 1951-1964; Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 4)
  - Chagall, Marc. Alfred Werner:Chagall, 1966 (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 5)
  - Chagall, Marc. Alfred Werner:Chagall: Watercolors and Gouaches Typescripts, 1970 (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 6)
  - Chagall, Marc. Alfred Werner:Chagall: Watercolors and Gouaches Reviews, 1970 (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 7)
  - Chagall, Marc. Lectures by Alfred Werner, Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 8)
  - Chagall, Marc. Typescripts of essays on Chagall by Werner, Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 9-10)
  - Chagall, Marc. Copies of published articles on Chagall by Werner, 1957-1977 (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 11)
  - Chagall, Marc. Reviews of books on Chagall by Werner. Typescripts, Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 12)
  - Chagall, Marc. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 13-14)
  - Chagall, Marc. Notes on Chagall windows, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 15)
  - Chagall, Marc. Libby Wigdor Seaberg:Four Books Illustrated by Marc Chagall. M.A. thesis, 1963 (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 16)
  - Chagall, Marc. Student papers on Chagall, 1974; Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 17)
  - Chagall, Marc. Clippings, materials on exhibits, in English, 1954-1977 (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 18-20)
  - Chagall, Marc. Clippings, materials on exhibits, in French, Hebrew, Spanish, 1944-1973 (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 21)
  - Chagall, Marc. Clippings, materials on exhibits, in German, 1950-1977 (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 22)
  - Chagall, Marc. Reviews of books about Chagall, 1956-1971 (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 23)
  - Chagall, Marc. Catalogs of exhibits, Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 24)
  - Chagall, Marc. Photographs of Chagall, Chagall's works, Undated (Box 2 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 25)
  - Degas, Edgar. Correspondence re: research on Degas monograph, 1967-1968 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 1)
  - Degas, Edgar. Alfred Werner:Degas Pastels. Typescripts, notes on paintings, 1968 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 2)
  - Degas, Edgar. Typescripts of essays on Degas by Werner, Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 3)
  - Degas, Edgar. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 4)
  - Degas, Edgar. Photographs of works by Degas, Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 5)
  - Degas, Edgar. Clippings and catalogs, 1936-1969 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 6)
  - Dürer, Albrecht. Alfred Werner:The Drawings of Albrecht Dürer. Typescripts including shorter essays, notes, 1970; Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 7)
  - Dürer, Albrecht. Clippings, in English and German, 1936-1969 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 8)
  - Dufy, Raoul. Alfred Werner:Raoul Dufy. Typescripts; also typescripts of shorter articles, notes, 1953; Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 9)
  - Dufy, Raoul. Copies of published articles on Dufy by Werner, 1964-1968 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 10)
  - Dufy, Raoul. Clippings, 1953-1969 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 11)
  - Gauguin, Paul. Alfred Werner:Paul Gauguin. Typescripts, 1967 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 12)
  - Gauguin, Paul. Typescripts of articles by Werner on Gauguin; also copies of published articles, 1958-1959 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 13)
  - Gauguin, Paul. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 14)
  - Gauguin, Paul. Clippings, catalogs, 1949-1968 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 15)
  - Gross, Chaim. Alfred Werner:Chaim Gross: Watercolors and Drawings Typescripts including shorter essays, 1979 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 16)
  - Gross, Chaim. Notes, handwritten and typed; Clippings, 1953-1977 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 17)
  - Inness, George. Alfred Werner:Inness Landscapes Typescripts, 1973 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 18-19)
  - Inness, George. Alfred Werner:Inness Landscapes Reviews, 1973 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 20)
  - Inness, George. Typescripts of short articles on Inness by Werner, Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 21)
  - Inness, George. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 22)
  - Inness, George. Clippings, 1925-1979 (Box 3 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 23-24)
  - Klimt, Gustav. Alfred Werner:One hundred drawings. Typescripts; also typescripts of shorter articles, published article, 1959; 1972; Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 1)
  - Klimt, Gustav. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 2)
  - Klimt, Gustav. Clippings, catalogs, 1960-1976 (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 3)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Correspondence re: research on Modigliani monographs, 1961-1965 (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 4)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Alfred Werner:Modigliani, the sculptor and Amedeo Modigliani. Typescripts, various versions, 1962; 1966 (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 5)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Typescripts of short articles on Modigliani by Werner, Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 6-7)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Copies of published articles by Werner on Modigliani, 1951-1964 (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 8)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 9-10)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Photographs of Modigliani artwork, Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 11)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Clippings, catalogs, in English, 1929-1966 (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 12-13)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Clippings, in French, 1930-1963 (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 14)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Clippings, in German, 1931-1968 (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 15)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Clippings, other languages, 1930-1962 (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 16)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo. Typescripts of articles by others, students, 1961-1974; Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 17)
  - Munch, Edvard. Alfred Werner:The Graphic Works of Edvard Munch, 1979 (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 18)
  - Munch, Edvard. Typescripts of short articles on Munch by Werner, Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 19)
  - Munch, Edvard. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 20)
  - Munch, Edvard. Clippings, exhibit information, primarily in English, 1944-1976 (Box 4 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 21)
  - Pascin, Jules [Julius Pincas]. Correspondence re: research for Pascin monographs, 1958-1960 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 1)
  - Pascin, Jules. Alfred Werner:Pascin and Pascin: 110 drawings. Typescripts, various versions, 1962; 1972 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 2-3)
  - Pascin, Jules. Alfred Werner: Pascin, 1962 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 4)
  - Pascin, Jules. Typescripts of short articles on Pascin by Werner, Undated (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 5-6)
  - Pascin, Jules. Clippings of articles on Pascin by Werner, 1955-1960 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 7)
  - Pascin, Jules. Notes, handwritten and typed, Undated (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 8-11)
  - Pascin, Jules. Catalogs of exhibits, 1931-1979 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 12)
  - Pascin, Jules. Clippings, in English, French, German, 1931-1969 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 13-14)
  - Redon, Odilon. Correspondence re: research on Redon monograph, 1969 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 15)
  - Redon, Odilon. Alfred Werner:The Graphic Works of Odilon Redon and typescripts of short articles on Redon, 1969; Undated (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 16)
  - Redon, Odilon. Notes, handwritten and typed. Undated. Catalogs, clippings, 1926-1969 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 17)
  - Schreck, Michael. Correspondence with Michael Schreck, 1926-1969; 2 L. (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 18)
  - Schreck, Michael. Typescript of article on Schreck, notes for monograph by Werner:Michael Schreck sculpture, 1975 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 19)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Correspondence re: research for Soutine monograph, 1972-1976 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 20)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Alfred Werner:Chaim Soutine. Typescripts, various versions, 1977 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 21-22)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Alfred Werner:Chaim Soutine. Colorplate descriptions, typescripts, 1977 (Box 5 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 23)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Alfred Werner:Chaim Soutine. Colorplate descriptions, typescripts, 1977 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 1)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Alfred Werner:Chaim Soutine. Miscellaneous photocopied texts, 1977 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 2)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Typescripts of short articles on Soutine by Werner, Undated (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 3)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Clippings of articles on Pascin by Werner, 1948-1972 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 4)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Notes, handwritten and typewritten, Undated (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 5-8)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Notes, bibliography, primarily handwritten, Undated (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 9)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Clippings, in English; student papers, 1928-1977 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 10-11)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Clippings in French, German, 1927-1973 (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 12)
  - Soutine, Chaim. Photographs of artwork, Undated (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 13)
  - Soyer, Moses. Alfred Werner:Moses Soyer. Proofs, 1970 (Oversized 22, Folder 13)
  - Soyer, Moses. Alfred Werner:Moses Soyer. Typescripts; also typescripts of short articles on Soyer. Notes, handwritten and typed, 1970; Undated (Box 6 (4-Writings: Monographs of Artists), Folder 14)